What's up guys, welcome back to my channel.
I hope you're having a lovely day today.
And I hope it gets even better from watching this video.
Today we're chatting all about how to actually become a happy person.
Like how to live a life that's authentic to you.
Meaningful and fulfilling and just a life that you're excited to wake up to.
Because who doesn't want that.
I honestly know a little something about this topic.
Because I used to be so incredibly unhappy.
I was at a mental hospital. I was a bad, bad, bad time.
And I dedicated myself to completely turn my life around.
And actually create a life for myself that I love.
And I'm excited about you really can turn your life around.
But even if your situation is not that dramatic.
Even if you're just in a little bit of a funk.
Or you're just trying to find some tips to be even happier.
You're in the right place.
By the way I have so much to say about this topic.
So if at the end of the video.
You want to see more.
You just let me know
And I'll do a part two
But today we're gonna really dive in
And we're gonna do a strategic step-by-step guide to become happy
I've got some exercises. Some journaling problems.
And I think it's also so important to really understand a topic
To make a difference. So we're going to dive into all of that
But if you're new here
Hi, I'm Nicka. I make videos all about self improvement
And I like to make them very strategic organized to-do list form
So you can actually make a big change
So if that works for you
I would love for you to subscribe and stick around
I also have my social media
If you want to see more of my personal life
And we can keep these chats going also
I finally launched the Notion template
You guys have been waiting for it: it's called a life design planner
So link it down below
If you've been waiting for it
Thank you for your patience.
It's basically where you can set and track your habits.
Your goals and your routines.
And you can also plan your months, your weeks.
Your days and there's so much more.
So I'll leave a link to that below.
As well as a video that I did.
Where I went over the whole system, if you're interested already.
Now let's get into how to actually be happy.
We're gonna start with understanding your core values.
Because I feel that's the most important thing
When it comes to your happiness and it's something
I don't hear many people talk about living a happy life
Means that you're living in accordance with your core values
So when you're committed to your core values
You're naturally prioritizing things that make you feel happy
Things that fulfill you and are important to you
So the simple guide or our compass to happiness is to figure out
What our core values are which we'll get to
And then commit to them and prioritize them
We're going to imagine what it's like
When this is not working when it's the opposite
So we're gonna talk about self-sacrificing
Which is such a common thing to do when you're unhappy
I used to do this
So it basically means you're prioritizing everyone else and what everyone else wants
You're basically a people pleaser
You're doing things that you think you should be doing
And things that you know make you seem like a good girl
And you're successful and you're amazing in the eyes of whoever
And if that's not in alignment with your values
And what you actually find meaningful and important
Of course you're going to be unhappy
Because you are spending so much of your time
Doing the things that you actually don't really care about and don't find meaningful
And what ends up happening is that you literally wake up to a life
That doesn't even feel like your own. You're living someone else's life
So let's say you are born very creative
And let's just imagine your core values are creativity and freedom
That is what actually makes you happy. What makes you feel alive
What makes your life feel meaningful and fulfilling?
But you grew up with a mom whose main priority is status.
And how you all as a family appear to your community.
To the neighborhood, to whoever. And she basically raised you to become a doctor.
So let's say you go along with that.
Let's say you don't wanna disappoint your mom.
And you want to please everyone, and you go into medicine.
Obviously you're not gonna be very happy.
Because medicine is not really a career that I would choose for someone.
Who's very creative and wants to be free.
It's the opposite of that, just the school part.
A loan would be bearable to someone.
Who just wants to be creative and free.
Let's talk about two really important things.
That might make starting to live in accordance with your values